<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Temporary Expert on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</title>
    <link>http://blog.alden.website/categories/temporary-expert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Temporary Expert on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 23:32:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.alden.website/categories/temporary-expert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxonomies Systems</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/taxonomies-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 23:32:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/taxonomies-systems/</guid>
      <description>List of Taxonomies All ideas for coherent taxonomies  Energy Types (Country by Country Energy Mix) -  high renewable mostly coal mostly nuclear mostly gas import/export ratio  Policy Goals  Seeking investment Building infrastructure Making revenue Reducing carbon admissions National security Political kick-backs Prop up the failing coal industry to own the libs (Just the US) Reducing city pollution Don&amp;rsquo;t rock the boat  Market Structures and Regulatory Regimes  Deregulated generation to transmission markets Regulated vertically integrated private utilities State-run vertically integrated utilities State/private grey area uh oh zone  Ownership (who owns what where and what power do they have)  Power of generation owners&amp;rsquo; lobbying (not sure how to measure) Acumulated wealth of energy investors and company owners as % of GDP   Due to the vastness and scope of nations&amp;rsquo; global energy policies I have been imagining so far pursuing a scattershot approach, with a few entries from different categories, say, for example, an entry on Japan&amp;rsquo;s nuclear energy policies, an entry on FERC chairman Kevin J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nation State Energy Policy</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/2018/09/11/energy-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/2018/09/11/energy-map/</guid>
      <description>https://vimeo.com/289321256
That a light bulb turns on is a horrendous miracle. Each and every electron that passes through the bulb has to be generated at almost the exact same second as the bulb is turned on, and if too many or too few electrons are created and pushed out through the electric grid the whole system can fail. The reliability of the entire system is founded on the bedrock of federal regulation, the prime directive of which is that THE LIGHTS MUST REMAIN ON.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>