<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Temporary Expert on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</title>
    <link>http://blog.alden.website/categories/temporary-expert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Temporary Expert on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 18:31:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.alden.website/categories/temporary-expert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Heaven Is a Waste Place Research Summary and Reflection</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/heaven-is-a-waste-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 18:31:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/heaven-is-a-waste-place/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In the end everything&amp;rsquo;s garbage&amp;rdquo; - Nick DiMola (one of my experts)
&amp;ldquo;Trash carries dystopia within&amp;rdquo; - Maite Zubiaurre
Heaven Is A Waste Place is a simulated corporation, The Ongoing Now Corporation, and the space in which it is simulated. It is part office role play and part doomsday cult. The goal of TONCO and its employees is to find new uses for waste after the apocalypse, and maybe a new, more holy way of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ongoing Now</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/the-ongoing-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 02:43:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/the-ongoing-now/</guid>
      <description>Inspired in part by seasteaders and other such cults which are entirely engaged in a utopia-building project even if that utopia looks like a nightmare to outsiders, I&amp;rsquo;ve begun building my own mythology of The Ongoing Now Corporation.
TON Corp is a corporate cult created by Theong Oingnow for the purpose of preparing for the Bow Sink, the day that Noah&amp;rsquo;s ark finally capsizes.
Preparations include the collection, analysis, and categorization of various discarded objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trash Moods</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/trash-moods/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 03:51:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/trash-moods/</guid>
      <description>Garbage Man KITH Smart Pipe Garbage Story</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trash Research Hub</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/trash-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 03:17:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/trash-research/</guid>
      <description> Running Bibliography
Daily Practice
Research Links  Propublica on Deadly Garbage Collection
 Mob and Garbage
 Space Debris
 More Space Debris
 GPS Tracking
 Incineration
 Portland Garbage Chronicles 1
 Portland Garbage Chronicles 2
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sandbox</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/sandbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 03:13:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/sandbox/</guid>
      <description>Does garbage conceal our dreams for the future? Is &amp;lsquo;throwing out&amp;rsquo; a hopeful act?  Do we remake ourselves with each discard? The Life Changing Magic of Throwing Out? What is &amp;ldquo;trash&amp;rdquo; culture? Junk food? Jerry Springer? Garbage / the lesser than.
A cockroach literally, actually crawled across my monitor just now. Cleansing and purging. Removal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draft Energy Field Guide</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/draft-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 14:42:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/draft-guide/</guid>
      <description>I made a draft of my field guide using the time honored &amp;ldquo;paper prototype&amp;rdquo; method. Corporate aesthetics, coming apart at the wheels. I used a hacky scan tool with Google photos to get these pictures of the draft since I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to run in the rain to the library for a real scan, hence the weird banners, but I actually think they fit the overall aesthetic well, though it washed out the color a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxonomies Systems</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/taxonomies-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 23:32:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/tempexp/taxonomies-systems/</guid>
      <description>List of Taxonomies All ideas for coherent taxonomies  Energy Types (Country by Country Energy Mix) -  high renewable mostly coal mostly nuclear mostly gas import/export ratio  Policy Goals  Seeking investment Building infrastructure Making revenue Reducing carbon admissions National security Political kick-backs Prop up the failing coal industry to own the libs (Just the US) Reducing city pollution Don&amp;rsquo;t rock the boat  Market Structures and Regulatory Regimes  Deregulated generation to transmission markets Regulated vertically integrated private utilities State-run vertically integrated utilities State/private grey area uh oh zone  Ownership (who owns what where and what power do they have)  Power of generation owners&amp;rsquo; lobbying (not sure how to measure) Acumulated wealth of energy investors and company owners as % of GDP   Due to the vastness and scope of nations&amp;rsquo; global energy policies I have been imagining so far pursuing a scattershot approach, with a few entries from different categories, say, for example, an entry on Japan&amp;rsquo;s nuclear energy policies, an entry on FERC chairman Kevin J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nation State Energy Policy</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/2018/09/11/energy-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/2018/09/11/energy-map/</guid>
      <description>https://vimeo.com/289321256
That a light bulb turns on is a horrendous miracle. Each and every electron that passes through the bulb has to be generated at almost the exact same second as the bulb is turned on, and if too many or too few electrons are created and pushed out through the electric grid the whole system can fail. The reliability of the entire system is founded on the bedrock of federal regulation, the prime directive of which is that THE LIGHTS MUST REMAIN ON.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nation State Energy Policy</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/2018/09/11/energy-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/2018/09/11/energy-map/</guid>
      <description>https://vimeo.com/289321256
That a light bulb turns on is a horrendous miracle. Each and every electron that passes through the bulb has to be generated at almost the exact same second as the bulb is turned on, and if too many or too few electrons are created and pushed out through the electric grid the whole system can fail. The reliability of the entire system is founded on the bedrock of federal regulation, the prime directive of which is that THE LIGHTS MUST REMAIN ON.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>