<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title> on  </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peñabots, Digital Obfuscation, and Government Trolling</title>
      <link>/2018/02/15/312/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/15/312/</guid>
      <description>In the first class I mentioned peñabots as an example of government social media manipulation. Rather than define them myself I&amp;#8217;ll lean on the Wikipedia page definition: &amp;#8220;the name given to what analysts believe to be a network of automated accounts on social media used by the Mexican government to spread pro-government propaganda and to marginalize dissenting opinions in social media&amp;#8221;. Though not the first institutionally-organized trolling operation they stand apart for their sophistication, their effectiveness at shutting down oppositional organizing, and their use in a nominally non-authoritarian government (although one with a deep history of media manipulation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ken Wark on Chantal Mouffe</title>
      <link>/2018/02/02/ken-wark-on-chantal-mouffe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/02/ken-wark-on-chantal-mouffe/</guid>
      <description>For my transcription exercise I wanted to pick something that was
a) short enough so that I could transcribe the whole thing
b) interesting enough that I wouldn&amp;#8217;t mind listening to it over and over again
c) spoken slowly enough that I would only have to pause and rewind ten seconds 500 times and not 1000.
I&amp;#8217;d recently watched to MacKenzie Wark&amp;#8217;s edutainment video on Chantal Mouffe for DIS magazine (now just DIS?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychographic Categorization Neural Network Simulator 2000</title>
      <link>/2017/12/11/psychographic-categorization-neural-network-simulator-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/11/psychographic-categorization-neural-network-simulator-2000/</guid>
      <description>For my computational media final project I wanted to make a game about Cambridge Analytica and about the current cultural moment in data science and AI. I have seen the rise of the imperative to make one&amp;#8217;s identity known and intelligible for collection online by various state and corporate actors as a sinister reach to further institutional control over the everyday, but I also think that the practice of psychographics is a silly pseudoscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypt vs Mausoleum</title>
      <link>/2017/11/20/crypt-vs-mausoleum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/20/crypt-vs-mausoleum/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite word games to play is to try to suss out the grey areas of meaning with seemingly well established words (e.g. what foot angle and distance of leaving the floor differentiates a &amp;#8216;tap&amp;#8217; from a &amp;#8216;step&amp;#8217;, in what ways are the aesthetic associations of a crypt different from those of a mausoleum). Kind of a useless semiotics examing the edge case value of a word (how much mist on a misty morning differentiates a bog from a swamp).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Digital Public Space</title>
      <link>/2017/11/16/make-a-digital-public-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/16/make-a-digital-public-space/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by the near extinct website guestbook and completely extinct methods of phone phreaking, I wanted to make something that felt as unfinished and wide open with potential as the &amp;#8220;old&amp;#8221; web of 1992 &amp;#8211; 2001.
Please participate: https://tinyurl.com/y7tvrusf
Communication between users in this space is possible but only through &amp;#8220;hacks&amp;#8221; of the intended use. There is no security and everything can be seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haunted Dollhouse Planning</title>
      <link>/2017/11/15/haunted-dollhouse-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/15/haunted-dollhouse-planning/</guid>
      <description>At this point I have gotten the basic Google home API working on my raspberry pi and have started manipulating the methods of interaction (changing the trigger word, changing the voices) and have started to work on building a specific Google home Action. Still to do is build the haunted dollhouse enclosure. Since the basic first interaction I want users to have with the haunted doll is to knock on the dollhouse door, I wanted to first set up a basic knock and open circuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Cheese Index</title>
      <link>/2017/11/06/world-cheese-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/06/world-cheese-index/</guid>
      <description>I really wanted to work with the twitter API and to show data in real time. I started working with the word cheese just to test it out and I ended up sticking with it throughout the process.
You can observer cheeses here.
And see code here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haunted Dolls and Things</title>
      <link>/2017/11/01/haunted-dolls-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/01/haunted-dolls-and-things/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking mostly &amp;#8211; but somewhat disjointedly &amp;#8211; about haunted dolls as relational to AI and various societal-level fears. The doll as feminine artifact rendered creepy by autonomous movement and malicious intent is drawing parallels for me to visions of consumer-level AI &amp;#8211; which frequently is embodied feminized labor &amp;#8211; disrupting human civilization, both on the level of job displacement and as genocidal overlords. Many questions arise. At what depth of the uncanny valley does misogyny lie?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Button Game</title>
      <link>/2017/10/30/button-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/30/button-game/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m in the middle of changing hosts for my blog so I will keep this entry short. I made a game involving clicking DOM buttons&amp;#8230; a lot.
You can see the code for the game here.
And you can play the game here.
&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi Five Machine</title>
      <link>/2017/10/25/hi-five-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/25/hi-five-machine/</guid>
      <description>For our midterm Ridwan and I thought it would be really funny to make a machine that claims to give a high five but actually fakes you out every time.
Aesthetically it reminds me a bit of the toilet hand from Zelda.
Inside it has an arduino, two metal gear servos on a pan/tilt bracket meant for camera tracking controlling the hand, an HC- SR04 distance sensor, and an LCD screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circle Game with Tracking</title>
      <link>/2017/10/23/circle-game-with-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/23/circle-game-with-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
I overhauled some of the code from my project last week so that events would only happen once so that the player would not experience an event more than once. I&amp;#8217;d like to implement some further tracking so that the narrative would change depending on what the user had done previously but I didn&amp;#8217;t finish that in a playable way.
You can see the improved code here.
I put a playable version of it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy Lense Kickstarter Campaign</title>
      <link>/2017/10/20/empathy-lense-kickstarter-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/20/empathy-lense-kickstarter-campaign/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;#8217;d like to thank Jason, Rick, and most importantly of all, Archibald! Thanks to bensound.com for the use of his music.
&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Card</title>
      <link>/2017/10/18/business-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/18/business-card/</guid>
      <description>Side A of the business card:
I really liked the hands and eyes that I had going in my show poster, so I decided that I wanted the same kind of thing for my business card. I wasn&amp;#8217;t really sure what to put for my &amp;#8220;title&amp;#8221; so that is just a placeholder for now. The font I used was &amp;#8220;Gil Sans&amp;#8221; and I took my Twitter and Github icons from their media packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Controller for My P5 Game</title>
      <link>/2017/10/18/making-a-controller-for-my-p5-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/18/making-a-controller-for-my-p5-game/</guid>
      <description>(note all the code for these projects can be viewed on my Github here though I will make specific references to scripts down below).
One of my P5 projects that I am the happiest with is an interactive poetry/anti-game game that involves corralling a ball with the cursor to reveal a narrative. I decided I wanted to replace the mouse and cursor with a joystick, and that I wanted to use node, express, and a websocket to interface between P5 and the arduino.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circle Game</title>
      <link>/2017/10/16/circle-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/16/circle-game/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to make a game-as-interactive-poetry without clear goals but with player progress still mediated by &amp;#8220;points&amp;#8221;.
&amp;#8220;Points&amp;#8221; are displayed constantly in the upper left corner. Doing nothing makes the points go down, clicking and holding the circle in the center makes the points go up. I was thinking of &amp;#8220;cookie clicker&amp;#8221; type games (like the currently buzzing paper clip AI game) when I made this and how much I hate them for creating unintersting artificial rewards that my brain still loves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

