<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Future Scenarios on </title>
    <link>/categories/future-scenarios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Future Scenarios on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/future-scenarios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic Decision Making in Bureaucracy, Public Policy, and The City</title>
      <link>/2018-03-07-algorithmic-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018-03-07-algorithmic-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>Here you can see the slides from my research presentation And here is my executive summary
Reports, Research Papers, and Press Releases As a great resource for all of our classes&amp;rsquo; discussions on AI I want to point out first the AI Now annual report. AI Now Institute is a research institute (within NYU! we can go talk to them) focused on interdisciplinary research on the social impacts of AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peñabots, Digital Obfuscation, and Government Trolling</title>
      <link>/2018/02/15/312/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/15/312/</guid>
      <description>In the first class I mentioned peñabots as an example of government social media manipulation. Rather than define them myself I&amp;#8217;ll lean on the Wikipedia page definition: &amp;#8220;the name given to what analysts believe to be a network of automated accounts on social media used by the Mexican government to spread pro-government propaganda and to marginalize dissenting opinions in social media&amp;#8221;. Though not the first institutionally-organized trolling operation they stand apart for their sophistication, their effectiveness at shutting down oppositional organizing, and their use in a nominally non-authoritarian government (although one with a deep history of media manipulation).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>