<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electronictext on </title>
    <link>/categories/electronictext/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Electronictext on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/electronictext/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome To</title>
      <link>/2018/05/04/welcome-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/04/welcome-to/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking about a completely automated conference talk since I saw Hito Steyerl and Wendy Chun give a talk at The Guggenheim for Hito&amp;rsquo;s book launch in January. Much of the content of their conversation had to do with economies of labor in art, economies of presence in art, and of the demands on artists and their time and of the place of the &amp;lsquo;artist talk&amp;rsquo; within the art labor economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic_Bad_Generative_Synths.wav</title>
      <link>/2018/04/13/word-vector-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/13/word-vector-music/</guid>
      <description>For this assignment I fell off the generative text pathway and onto the well worn path of the media artist: bad generative music compositions with shiny new tools. On my Github feed I noticed that Rebecca Fiebrink had recently created a new repository called word2vec2osc and I realized that I could use word vectors plugged into Wekinator to train a bunch of sine wave generators to turn bodies of text into musical compositions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ken Wark on Chantal Mouffe</title>
      <link>/2018/02/02/ken-wark-on-chantal-mouffe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/02/ken-wark-on-chantal-mouffe/</guid>
      <description>For my transcription exercise I wanted to pick something that was
a) short enough so that I could transcribe the whole thing
b) interesting enough that I wouldn&amp;#8217;t mind listening to it over and over again
c) spoken slowly enough that I would only have to pause and rewind ten seconds 500 times and not 1000.
I&amp;#8217;d recently watched to MacKenzie Wark&amp;#8217;s edutainment video on Chantal Mouffe for DIS magazine (now just DIS?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>