<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Understanding Networks on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</title>
    <link>http://blog.alden.website/categories/understanding-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Understanding Networks on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 22:46:34 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.alden.website/categories/understanding-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RESTful VJing</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/undernet/RESTful-VJing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 22:46:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/undernet/RESTful-VJing/</guid>
      <description>Beverly and I decided to work on a quick VJing system. We started out doing research and interviewed a few people on the floor to ask them what they thought made for good VJing, and what made for bad VJing. The most consistent thing we heard was that the visuals should match the mood and timing of the music. Since beat syncing the visuals to the music might be hard with REST we decided to have two &amp;ldquo;modes&amp;rdquo; for the system, GIF mode and visuals mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Network Packets</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/undernet/my-network-packets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 22:56:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/undernet/my-network-packets/</guid>
      <description>My network map was more or less what I expected to see. Here&amp;rsquo;s the map from Herbivore. Note that my public IP&amp;rsquo;s threat level is low.
The TP-Link at 192.168.0.1 is, naturally, my router. The TP-Link at .100 is actually my wifi-enabled plug from the same manufacturer. The Amazon Technologies device is an Echo (running 64 bit Linux? I thought they ran &amp;lsquo;Amazon Fire&amp;rsquo; EDIT: looks like Fire OS has a Linux kernel), The Canon is a printer, the Pis are actually a single Pi connected via both wifi and ethernet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traced Routes</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/undernet/traceroutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 22:07:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/undernet/traceroutes/</guid>
      <description>The websites I visit most frequently are a little boring. According to what Chrome, my browser, suggests, my number one visited website is Twitter, followed by the (in?)famous data journalism blog FiveThirtyEight, then ScaryGoRound.com which is a webcomic I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading for almost 15 years, then Gmail (the Inbox flavor), then Github, and then my own blog which you are reading now. I think that last one is only because of how often I need to double check that my posts have actually made it online, not because of the love I have for my own posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Pong</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/2018/09/10/bad-pong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/2018/09/10/bad-pong/</guid>
      <description>I really like gesture controls, nothing makes me feel more like a technopagan completing a ritual than controlling something on my screen just by waving my hands around, so I decided that I wanted to control the paddle in just such a manner. Initially in order to make some kind of gestural control system I wanted to put a camera on a raspberry pi and train it to recognize particular hand shapes, but that sounded like overkill and I missed the Arduino IDE too much not to take advantage of the opportunity to use it again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>