<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>100 Days on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</title>
    <link>http://blog.alden.website/categories/100-days/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 100 Days on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 22:09:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.alden.website/categories/100-days/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 58: Climbing the Global Cyber Vandalism Ladder in Westminster, Crypto Airdrops, and the Shady Underworld of Monetized Link Shortening Services</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 22:09:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-58/</guid>
      <description>Today I felt like going for another hacked website, so I again searched for &amp;ldquo;hacked by&amp;rdquo; on Shodan like I did all the way back on day 18.
A Hacked Server on 94.76.219.226 There were so many results, I picked the first one I got, in the UK. It had ftp and ssh running, as well as email and the usual 80 and 443 webservers. It also had a cPanel login page running, cPanel being, in my experience, the most miserable way to run a webhost backend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 57: Shodaning Myself, Ye Olde Telnet Service, and the Weather Underground</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-57/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 17:30:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-57/</guid>
      <description>Yes today I Shodaned myself. Nothing shows up for my full name, thankfully, but &amp;ldquo;alden&amp;rdquo; has a lot of results.
The Weather Underground on 35.160.169.47 I picked a result in Boardman, Oregon, largely because of how charming it was. It&amp;rsquo;s just a telnet server, running on port 23 and mirrored on port 3000. You almost never see telnet anymore these days, since it&amp;rsquo;s been primarily replaced with the much more secure ssh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 56: Buying Souvenirs in Bethlehem, Schneider Electric spaceLYnk, EXIF Data, and Does It Count as a Pilgrimage If You Are Just Remotely Opening and Closing Gates via a Store&#39;s Insecure SCADA System?</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-56/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 12:01:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-56/</guid>
      <description>I saw a search today for someone looking for spaceLYnk logic controllers, a kind of logic controller for SCADA systems made by Schneider Electric (SCADA, if you remember from day 30, stands for supervisory control and data acquisition).
spaceLYnk SCADA System on 213.6.102.238 There were quite a few results from all over the place, but I noticed that most of them didn&amp;rsquo;t have visualizations of the system. So I picked one that had the whole system mapped out, in Palestine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 55: Dancing with Skunks and Annotating Goats in Fremont, Ornamental Hermits, Gopherspace, and the Mysteries of Time</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-55/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 13:39:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-55/</guid>
      <description>Some Cisco routers say &amp;ldquo;SAN FRANCISCO&amp;rdquo; when telneting into them, and so someone had searched for that on Shodan looking for these routers (they say other things too of course, but that&amp;rsquo;s just an easily searchable commonality). That kind of dragnet obviously pulls in a lot of other stuff too and I was particularly taken with one result.
An Ornamental Hermit on 74.207.243.202 What caught my eye on this IP was that Shodan was indicating that it was running gopher on port 70.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 54: Pumping Your Own in Saint-Denis</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-54/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 19:43:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-54/</guid>
      <description>I read this old blog post from 2015 talking about how many internet connected pumps at gas stations were vulnerable to hacking. I wanted to see if anything had really changed in the last four years.
Automated Tank Gauge on 81.248.205.246 Based on that blog post it seemed that the best thing to search for was &amp;ldquo;I20100&amp;rdquo;. I immediately found several thousand results and yes all of them seemed to be accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 53: Just an IoT Highway Sign in Los Angeles</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 19:46:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-53/</guid>
      <description>I had a red eye flight last night and am deliriously sleepy, and somewhere in this state bubbled up a strong desire to find an electronic highway billboard and read what it said remotely. I read Skyline makes internet connected billboards and use port 161. So I got searching.
A Skyline Sign on 173.4.137.205 Skyline manufactures quite a few different kinds of signs, but all of them are related to car transit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 52: The Littleborough Losers in Ramsgate, Having a Few Pints with the Lads, Fantasy Football Since 1995, Rick&#39;s Footy Challenge, and Wayne Rooney the True Ledge</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 23:48:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-52/</guid>
      <description>I saw an amazing search on Shodan today, it was just named &amp;ldquo;self-explanatory&amp;rdquo; and the search was just for the word &amp;ldquo;losers&amp;rdquo;. How could I say no?
Littleborough Losers on 94.7.201.171 The results were pretty varied, there&amp;rsquo;s apparently a sex kink that has to do with being dominated and called a loser and so quite a few results were communities related to that, but I found a result in England that more closely fits my particular kink: 90s web design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 51: Keeping Abreast of the Hyperlocal Weather in Uppsala, Yawcam, and Multinational Pest Control</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 07:29:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-51/</guid>
      <description>A quick webcam day as I was busy with a conference most of the day.
A Yawcam on 85.224.37.79 This time I went looking for &amp;ldquo;yawcam&amp;rdquo;, a webcam server software whose name stands for Yet Another Webcam. Like most free DIY webcam servers the default seems to be &amp;ldquo;completely insecure&amp;rdquo;, and I found quite a few interesting cameras, but chose one in Sweden that was running on port 8888. I love this because this person has so clearly come up with the exact perfect hack for their needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 50: Pondering a Loading Bay in Saint Petersburg</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 10:36:25 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-50/</guid>
      <description>To celebrate my 50th day and the fact that there haven&amp;rsquo;t been any interesting new searches the past few days, I went to find an open RTSP video stream from an IP camera.
Security Camera on 85.143.138.242 Unfortunately after searching for awhile I only found one open stream, from Russia, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly interesting. Definitely a warehouse or factory or some kind of industrial building. If only I could make out that sign in the upper corner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 49: Solving Crimes and Protecting the Innocent in Paris</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 22:23:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-49/</guid>
      <description>Another boring day on the shared searches. I decided to search for IPs with &amp;ldquo;dev environment&amp;rdquo; in the title, hoping to find something good.
Ace Attorney Online on 163.172.128.52 Many of the results were pretty interesting and I think it&amp;rsquo;s a fruitful search overall, but one result in France stood out to me. It&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;developer environment&amp;rdquo; for a webpage running on port 8080 dedicated to fan-made versions of the popular Ace Attorney games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 48: Processing Wood Products in Piet Retief, Dahua Botnets, MikroTik Botnets, and Particle Board</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 15:47:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-48/</guid>
      <description>Kind of a weird one today. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like any of the searches I&amp;rsquo;d seen so I decided to search for anything that had &amp;ldquo;production plant&amp;rdquo; in the title.
A Woodchem Production Plant on 154.126.209.18 I wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely sure what I was looking for, but got several dozen results. I decided to pick one in South Africa. On port 80 it was running a login for a Dahua Technology device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 47: Looking at Feet in Tokyo</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 23:37:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-47/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m busy preparing for a trip today and running errands so a quick one today. I found another Steven Wu webcam entirely by accident, just browsing Shodan&amp;rsquo;s webserver snapshots (see day 38 if Steven Wu doesn&amp;rsquo;t ring a bell). I like the Steven Wu cameras. The very simple interface, the snapshot approach. Feels right.
IP Camera on 110.5.43.249 The camera&amp;rsquo;s webserver is running on port 81. Specifically what interested me about this webcam was its area of focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 46: Getting Connected in Vietnam, GPON ONT, VNPT, and the Mysteries of DNS Addressing</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 10:37:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-46/</guid>
      <description>Someone was really looking for GPONs today, as I saw at least three searches for GPON related devices. What&amp;rsquo;s a GPON you wonder? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out together.
VNPT GPON ONT on 14.161.15.80 GPON stands for Gigabit Passive Optical Network. Though the real details of how they work escape me, it seems that they are a commonly used device by ISPs to separate out cable traffic between customers, frequently referred to as the &amp;ldquo;last mile&amp;rdquo; between the ISP and the end customer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 45: Filferro in Empuriabrava, .NET Games, eMule, Pokémon Armageddon, and the Joy Only Known to Those Who Keep Their Campsites Cow Free</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 17:56:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-45/</guid>
      <description>Another day another search. Today I found a shared search for &amp;ldquo;emule&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s an emule?&amp;rdquo; I asked myself, and dove in.
An eMule on 87.216.176.220 eMule is an &amp;ldquo;electronic mule&amp;rdquo;, duh. It&amp;rsquo;s a kind of peer to peer software, different from bittorent, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure exactly how. Every explanation I&amp;rsquo;ve found on how it works is a bit over my head, or at least over my attention span. It seemed like eMule was mostly popular in Europe, and I picked a result in Spain with eMule running on port 8000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 44: Dealing with the Devil in Quebec, Repetitive Jetpack Death, Dr. Cheetos&#39; Pain Chamber, Ludum Dare 43, Unity Web GL, and What Happened to Dave?</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 20:51:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-44/</guid>
      <description>Saw a great search today, this for Unity Engine Web Players. Unity is a hugely popular 3D game engine, primarily used for making video games but has a wide range of applications, including workflow simulation, architectural prototyping, and filmmaking. Typically Unity outputs run as stand alone applications, but it also has the ability to output applications for the web via Web GL.
Unity Web GL on 52.15.155.102 There were about 600 results for this search and I picked the first result I found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 43: Jamming Out in Centerville, Bundesliga Fans, and the Discreet Charm of the Presentation Page</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 21:50:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-43/</guid>
      <description>I decided to double dip on AV receivers since someone was going so deep on them the past few days. Today I decided to look at Pioneer.
Pioneer AV Receiver on 167.142.82.87 I mostly know pioneer as a manufacturer of CDJs, and had no idea that they had a diverse product line beyond DJ equipment. They make bike equipment and accessories, a wide variety of audio equipment, and some kinds of computer electronics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 42: Party Mode in Kleppestø, Yamaha Receivers, and Incredible Web Design</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 22:41:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-42/</guid>
      <description>I saw that someone was searching for quite a few different types of AV receivers today. I decided to look into one of their searches, this one for Yamaha receiver.
Yamaha AV Recievers on 90.149.252.214 I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what the typical use-case for remote control of an AV receiver is. Maybe if you run a cafe and you want to make sure your untrustworthy employees don&amp;rsquo;t make the music too loud while you&amp;rsquo;re out?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 41: Mining for Innovation in Abu Dhabi, Trapped in the Multiverse of Project Validation, Haunted by the Lightbulb of Ideas, Tasked with an Eternity of Teamwork Communication Adjustment</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 23:19:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-41/</guid>
      <description>I saw someone searching for &amp;ldquo;snapchat&amp;rdquo; today. &amp;ldquo;YOLO&amp;rdquo;, I said to myself, and dived in.
Fujairah Innovation Mine on 83.111.19.71 The search was in fact pulling up some of Snapchat&amp;rsquo;s production servers. Those were fairly boring however, though I did find something a little more interesting. This is a website for an organization called Fujairah Innovation Mine, which seems to be a typical tech startup incubator. The website was was running on port 7548 of the IP, so it clearly couldn&amp;rsquo;t be the official version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 40: Blue_7 in Beijing, GGGG, Evading Government Censures, Server Login Lists, Abandoned Blogs, Shadow Socks, Telegram Chat Rooms, and the Mystery of Using URLs as Passwords</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 17:20:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-40/</guid>
      <description>I spent so long trying to figure out what I found today that I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten how I found it. I think it was from someone&amp;rsquo;s search for &amp;ldquo;USB&amp;rdquo;, but I&amp;rsquo;m now unable to recreate the search.
A Mystery on 118.24.95.11 However I discovered this IP, I first arrived at what looked like a normal blog on port 8083. There is a very ~hacker~ image of a guy in ad hoody as the author&amp;rsquo;s picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 39: More TV Torrenting in Toronto, Reckless API Key Exposure, Sonarr, Radarr, Jackett, Ombi, and Deluge</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 20:29:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-39/</guid>
      <description>Saw a search just for &amp;ldquo;gmail.com&amp;rdquo;, I assume to look for anyone who put their email address into their service. I decided to take a look.
A Torrenting Operation on 162.157.129.215 I like this search because it&amp;rsquo;s device and service agnostic. I ended up just picking the first result and running with it, this one in Toronto. It turned out that the email address that brought me there belonged to the developer of a bittorent client named Deluge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 38: A Clothing Store in Moscow</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 12:11:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-38/</guid>
      <description>A quick cam day today because I&amp;rsquo;m a busy bee. I found a search awhile back for &amp;ldquo;Auther: Steven Wu&amp;rdquo;. Yes with the typo. It seems that Steven Wu wrote some server software for networked cameras back in maybe 2009 that is now used in a few different camera brands, all of which allow for snapshots to be taken without a password even if the video feed itself requires a password.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 37: Minitel</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 21:50:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-37/</guid>
      <description>Oh Minitel. I never expected to find you, here on the very World Wide Web that killed you.
3614 TEASER emulator on 62.210.93.204 I saw a recent search on Shodan for &amp;ldquo;ttyd terminal shell&amp;rdquo;. ttyd is a service for sharing your Terminal over the web, meaning that an insecure ttyd server would mean total access over someone&amp;rsquo;s computer (assuming they were porting root). I decided to take a look. Of the 12 results most were just named &amp;lsquo;ttyd - terminal&amp;rsquo; and most of those were inactive, but one stood out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 36: A Sick Beard in Hilversum, Usenet Is Still Around, Torrenting SuperUsers, and How Much of the Internet Is Just People Trying to Watch TV?</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 22:40:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-36/</guid>
      <description>The Shodan recent searches is a well that never runs dry. Today I saw someone searching for &amp;ldquo;Sickbeard&amp;rdquo;. What could that possibly be??
Sickbeard TV on 85.145.200.210 The search was named Sickbeard but the actual search was for &amp;ldquo;CherryPy/3.2.0rc1 This resource can be found at&amp;rdquo;. Looking into it, CherryPy is a python based framework for running webapps. It looks useful and I think I&amp;rsquo;ll log it into my toolkit for a later project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 35: Library Kiosks in Duchesne, Session Management Solutions, and True Friendship</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:16:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-35/</guid>
      <description>Saw an amazing search on Shodan today: someone searched for &amp;ldquo;kiosk&amp;rdquo; with the comment &amp;ldquo;lotta cool stuff&amp;rdquo;. Lotta cool stuff! How could I resist.
A Library Kiosk Management System on 104.239.140.99 Most of the kiosks seemed to be library kiosks, I even found one from my alma mater&amp;rsquo;s library! I ended up going with the first one that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t immediately figure out the purpose of. It was running some kind of web server on port 3000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 34: Listening to La Merde in Bonneuil-sur-marne, Logitech Servers, the Squeezebox, and Becoming the Ghost in the Wifi Connected Radio</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 01:21:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-34/</guid>
      <description>As many of my days now start, I began my morning by looking through the recent searches on Shodan. I found one for Logitech devices that looked kind of interesting and dove in.
Logitech Media Server on 82.64.23.201 I no longer remember why I picked this particular device since I did my searching in the morning and am writing at night. I think I was impressed by the number of ports it had open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 33: Propaganda in Pyongyang</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 20:55:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-33/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw someone had compiled a list of every Shodan-discovered server running in North Korea. To be honest I was a little surprised that there would be much outward-facing internet in North Korea, so I decided to take a look.
Media Ryugyong on 175.45.176.80 Most of the servers seemed to be mail servers, but some of them were running webpages. I picked the first one I found that was running a web page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 32: Red Lion Industrial Controls in a Remote US Location, Riding the XetaWave, the AirLink ACEmanager, Tank Batteries, and the Stack Overflow Answer that Launched 6000 Redirects</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 17:27:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-32/</guid>
      <description>Today I decided to go looking for for industrial control systems made by a company called Red Lion Controls. Red Lion makes controllers, touch screen operation panels, and a few other things besides. Reading Shodan I found that I could find them by searching for devices using port 789, which is the default port that Red Lion&amp;rsquo;s software uses to communicate.
A Red Lion Controller on 166.167.27.6 I just went with the first result, this one somewhere in the US on a Verizon wireless mobile network, and immediately got sucked into figuring out whatever was going on with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 31: Youth Volunteering in Guri, ePrinting, Jetdirect, Requiem for a Hewlett Packard, the State of Civil Society, and Hand Massages for the Elderly</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 21:23:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-31/</guid>
      <description>I saw a search on Shodan for &amp;ldquo;Jetdirect&amp;rdquo; with the tagline &amp;ldquo;unsecured printers&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;d recently heard a story about fans of the Youtuber PewDiePie using Shodan to hack into 50,000 printers to print messages about him so I thought maybe I could take a look and see maybe how they had done it.
HP Officejet Pro 8100 N811a on 121.161.211.66 Shodan showed 18,000 results for Jetdirect, with a plurality of them being in Korea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 30: Automating Buildings in Copenhagen, the BAS SCADA Industry, Expandable Controllers, Cloriūs, KeRo, and O&amp;J CTS A/S</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 22:37:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-30/</guid>
      <description>Today I decided to go looking for SCADA systems. SCADA stands for supervisory control and data acquisition and is a type of widely used industry management software, typically made bespoke for a particular factory or building. For a little more information I&amp;rsquo;ll let the man himself, Carl Gould, take it away.   SCADA Building Automation System on 80.71.129.61 Not really sure how to find one, I just searched on Shodan for &amp;ldquo;SCADA&amp;rdquo; hoping to reap rewards with little research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 29: Crypto World in Santa Monica, Trello Boards, Tokenization, and the Vectorialists</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 23:01:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-29/</guid>
      <description>I saw someone searching for &amp;ldquo;ICO&amp;rdquo;. At first I thought maybe it had something to do with the groundbreaking 2001 indie game, but after browsing some links I realized that no, it meant &amp;ldquo;Initial Coin Offering&amp;rdquo;, and yes this is another crypto thing.
CoinCircle&amp;rsquo;s ICOStats Tracker on 165.227.6.170 Most of the results on Shodan are websites and webservers, but I found one running on Digital Ocean that&amp;rsquo;s just a web app running on port 3000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 28: Joining the Electric World in Darmstadt</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 17:12:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-28/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw someone searching for &amp;ldquo;turbines&amp;rdquo;. An intriguing search, certainly, and at first I thought that they were looking for wind turbines. No however it seems that whoever it was just randomly searched turbines. I decided to roll with it and see what came up.
B-I-A Vertriebs GmbH on 82.165.151.127 I ended up deciding on the web server run by a German wholesaler for electricity parts named B-I-A Vertriebs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 27: A Connoisseur of Sorts in Shenzhen, Western Digital 2 Go, and Rest In Peace TwonkyMedia</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:04:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-27/</guid>
      <description>Saw somebody doing a search for &amp;ldquo;twonky&amp;rdquo;. What a name! I had to find out about it.
A Twonky Media Server on 14.155.113.144 Twonky is one of many personal media servers I&amp;rsquo;ve now run into, meant to run either on a network attached storage device or on a computer. The purpose I assume is to be able to stream your media from any devices on your network without having to worry about storying them locally (so if you&amp;rsquo;ve stolen a lot of blueray movie rips from bittorent and want to watch them on your phone or something).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 26: Multicasting in Siberia, UDP Packet Pixies, and Free Civ</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 22:22:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-26/</guid>
      <description>The other day I saw someone on Shodan searching for &amp;ldquo;udpxy&amp;rdquo;, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t determine what was going on with that because all of the results would give me 401 no auth errors. Today I realized that I could, of course, add &amp;ldquo;200 OK&amp;rdquo; to the search and only return successful connections. So I did.
A Udpxy Server on 5.136.117.163 There were only two results, both in Russia, so I picked the one that seemed a little more interesting, from Tomsk, Siberia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 25: Helping Strangers in Singapore</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 16:34:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-25/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw someone searching for &amp;ldquo;SingTel&amp;rdquo;, and had given a description of the search saying &amp;ldquo;what? no auth? W o a h&amp;rdquo;. Pretty compelling stuff, so I gave it a search myself. The actual query was a little more complicated, &amp;ldquo;Server: Arcadyan httpd 1.0 200 OK org:&amp;ldquo;Singtel Fibre Broadband&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;.
An Unsecured Router on 219.74.62.124 Every result for the search was in Singapore, which I realized is because Singtel is one of the largest ISPs and mobile network providers in Singapore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 24: Watching the News in Cheongju, IPTime Routers, Synology Yet Again, and TVheadend</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 17:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-24/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw a search just for &amp;ldquo;TVheadend&amp;rdquo; and I thought it looked like a weird name so I decided to investigate.
TVheadened Server on 125.181.166.200 TVheadend is an open source streaming server and recorder for streaming television on Linux, FreeBSD, or Android machines. I believe it works by intercepting television input and putting it into streamable format, which means that the machine running this server would need some kind of cable or radio tv receiver (maybe even a Dreambox 😄).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 23: Super Mediocrity in Albuquerque, Wifi Garage Doors, WebIOPi, and the Great Xylophone Saga of 2015</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 11:14:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-23/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s was a true delight, a real moment of striking gold, of finding something so beautifully weird that I can barely contain my excitement in writing this. Truly the spice of life, this. I started off wanting to find a wifi connected garage door, and I read that garage door openers are a common application of WebIOPi, which is a toolkit for Raspberry Pis to turn them into common IoT products via their GPIO pins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 22: Raising Cow Fighting Squid in Yilan</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 22:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-22/</guid>
      <description>I saw someone&amp;rsquo;s search for &amp;ldquo;Synology DiskStation&amp;rdquo; and even given our little foray into Synology back on day 20 I was ready to dive back into the world of the globe&amp;rsquo;s premier network attached storage maker.
A Prototype of a Taiwanese Farm&amp;rsquo;s Website on 114.34.78.222 The DiskStation promises &amp;ldquo;personal cloud storage&amp;rdquo; which to me sounds just like a personal server you connect to the internet, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just old fashioned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 21: POWERful Plates in Fargo, Digital Signage, Unsecured Pis, and the Cold Cold Midwest Winter</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 21:45:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-21/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw someone searching for &amp;ldquo;Screenly OSE&amp;rdquo; and actually gave a description for their search saying &amp;ldquo;screenly ose for the pi, think of a billboard system&amp;rdquo;. So I gave it a go.
A Raspberry Pi Digital Sign on 140.186.23.181 Screenly is a software for doing digital signage off of a Raspberry Pi. They have a &amp;ldquo;Pro&amp;rdquo; version for quite a bit of money ($20/month minumum but up to $800/month) and also an open source edition, which is what OSE stands for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 20: υηκηοωη ιδεηեτγ in France, Private Telephone Exchanges, Network Attached Storage, and Getting Lost in the Matrix</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 12:45:18 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-20/</guid>
      <description>Oh what a tangled web we weave. I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what&amp;rsquo;s going on with this one or how I got here, I wanted to explore a search I had seen on Shodan called &amp;ldquo;3cx servers bcn&amp;rdquo; but now I&amp;rsquo;m trapped in a digital hall of mirrors. 3CX is a private telephone exchange that sometimes runs over VoIP, and has servers that typically tend to run on 5001.
υηκηοωη ιδεηեτγ on 62.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 19: Never Trust Me With The WiFi</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 22:59:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-19/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m staying with a friend whose partner has a pretty serious media server set up (with 64TB! of content), and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take a look to see if I could find it on Shodan. And sure enough I could!
My Friend&amp;rsquo;s Media Server on 104.172.240.189 So I had previously seen a Plex service running on an IP back on day 9, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t investigate it too much because at the time I was focused on the irrigation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 18: Defaced Server in Walnut, Hacking in a Nutshell, These Jokes Don&#39;t Write Themselves!</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 23:35:30 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-18/</guid>
      <description>In what I hope will become an infrequently regular feature I decided today to look for an already hacked server that had been defaced. I had found one in the process of defacement on my very first day, but the fully defaced ones are interesting largely because of the tags left by the hackers themselves. I&amp;rsquo;m a little nervous about drawing attention to myself by publishing hacker tags in plaintext (easily found via Google alerts) so I&amp;rsquo;ll mostly be doing that via images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 17: An ATM in Perm, Russia and Just How Much Market Capture Does Windows 2000 Have Anyway?</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 12:43:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-17/</guid>
      <description>Today I thought it might be fun to find an ATM, largely because I wanted to answer the question &amp;ldquo;why connect an ATM to the internet with a static IP?&amp;rdquo; I checked for past Shodan searches for ATMs to see if I could find anyone else looking for some so I would know what to look for, and I was able to find someone else looking for ATMs from a brand named NCR, which work over port 169.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 16: A Serbian Highway</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 15:34:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-16/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty busy today with Processing Day so I&amp;rsquo;ll keep today&amp;rsquo;s short. Shodan may be best known for finding strangers&amp;rsquo; webcams, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gone for one yet because early on in this project I decided that on days when I don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of time I&amp;rsquo;d just find an unsecured webcam and grab a still image. Today is one of those days.
Someone&amp;rsquo;s Webcam in Belgrade on 109.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 15: Deftly Avoiding Turning On A Stranger&#39;s Lights in Bologna, the Commercial Level ESP8266, Getting Too Close with WiGLE, and What&#39;s the Deal with Home Automation Anyway?</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 11:01:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-15/</guid>
      <description>Another IoT home device today. At this point I&amp;rsquo;m picturing the people with these things basically having a Wallace and Gromit style lifestyle (note: I do have a wifi plug and yes this is my lifestyle). This one was inspired by another search I didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize, for &amp;ldquo;Sonoff&amp;rdquo;.
A Sonoff wifi enabled plug on 87.20.184.148 Sonoff is a company that makes IoT plugs and switches, as well as a couple of models of IoT fans and light bulbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 14: Startling Strangers in Vreden, DIY Home Automation, and the German Word for Waking Up in the Middle of the Night with the Realization That You Left Your Server Unsecured</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 07:04:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-14/</guid>
      <description>This is another find inspired by recent searches on Shodan. I saw searches &amp;ldquo;FHEM Home Automation&amp;rdquo; and I needed to know more.
Fhem Home Automation Server on 85.190.248.171 Every single result for FHEM was from Germany. So I picked the first one and got going. Looking up FHEM first on Google I found that it is an open source server software for doing home automation, built in perl and meant to be run on any kind of full time 24 /7 computer, like a Raspberry Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 13: Space X Email Server in Tokyo, No Not That Space X</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 14:37:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-13/</guid>
      <description>In honor of my spending about six hours on an airplane today I decided to search Shodan for &amp;ldquo;satellite&amp;rdquo; and, giving myself over to fate, pick the first result without looking at it.
The Email Server of a Long Defunct Conference at 163.44.163.77 Since I was inspired by the fact that my airplane is being serviced by satellite internet I was of course hoping that I would find the IP for a real actual space satellite, though I suspected I was more likely to find someone&amp;rsquo;s satellite internet router or satellite dish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 12: Influencer to Brand Marketplace and Authentic Content Platform in St Louis, Damaging My Klout Score via Unauthorized API Calls, GraphQL IDEs, and the Center of the Internet</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 20:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-12/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw a top search for something called &amp;ldquo;GraphQL&amp;rdquo;. Taking the bait on the unknown, I started looking.
A Startup Named Zipline&amp;rsquo;s API Staging Space on 184.169.231.191 The first thing I noticed about GraphQL&amp;rsquo;s distribution on Shodan was that it was all in the US. The second was that it was, by a huge margin, all in Ashburn, Virginia. After doing a quick google search I figured out that this is certainly because Amazon has so many datacenters there (leading it to be cheekily referred to as the &amp;ldquo;center of the internet&amp;rdquo;), and every GraphQL service seemed to be running on an Amazon EC2 instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 11: Machine Learning in Beijing and the Mysteries of 126 and 163</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 14:27:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-11/</guid>
      <description>Today I went looking for MongoDB databases. I used MongoDB back in Shawn Van Every&amp;rsquo;s servers class, I remember feeling pretty cool using a NoSQL database. Shodan indicated that MongoDB tends to work off of port 27017 so that&amp;rsquo;s where I started looking.
The Shell of Someone&amp;rsquo;s Machine Learning Blog on 35.185.145.24 I picked one of the first results I found on Shodan. According to Shodan it&amp;rsquo;s located in Singapore and hosted on Google Cloud services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 10: Reading License Plates in Louisiana, the Bygone Days of Java Webapps, and Spying on Cops</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:08:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-10/</guid>
      <description>I was feeling listless today and a bit grumpy, so I decided to look for something that I could be motivationally upset about: automatic license plate readers (ALPRs). These are a kind of surveillance camera that are frequently used by police forces or parking facility managers to track cars and car movement. You might have seen a kind of them attached to traffic signal beams to catch red light runners, but they are used far more widely than just that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 9: I Got Rickrolled by an Irrigation System in Los Vegas</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 20:30:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-9/</guid>
      <description>This is another one I found from looking at recent searches on Shodan. Someone searched for &amp;ldquo;BlueSpray irrigation&amp;rdquo; and I decided to follow their lead.
BlueSpray Wifi-Enabled Irrigation Controller (or maybe somebody&amp;rsquo;s pentesting playground) on 71.52.48.61 BlueSpray is a startup that makes an internet of things irrigation system for the consumer level (so for suburban lawns, not farms). If &amp;ldquo;internet of things lawn sprinkler&amp;rdquo; makes your eyes roll all the way back into your head well then this blog is for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 8: Mining Ethereum in Caracas, AMD GPUs, and Taking a Dip in the Nanopool</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:55:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-8/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago I noticed some people searching on Shodan for &amp;ldquo;ETH: total speed&amp;rdquo;. That didn&amp;rsquo;t mean anything to me so I took note of it and today decided to dig in.
An Ethereum Miner on 186.90.40.229 Almost all the results I found for this search in Shodan were running off of port 3001 (the ones that weren&amp;rsquo;t were on 9001), and tended to be in Russia, South Korea, or Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 7: Scammers in the Czech Republic, Cyrillic TLDs, and Hacking the Hackers</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 15:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-7/</guid>
      <description>Someone tried to phish me yesterday via text from a Los Vegas phone number. Fortunately I was able to figure out their IP address and, yes, their IP is on Shodan. Someone Trying to Phish Me on 146.120.89.201 I started out checking both номе.рф and xn&amp;ndash;e1ance.xn&amp;ndash;p1ai, which is the address the text message actually links to. In case you are wondering, and don&amp;rsquo;t want to read further, номе.рф is safe to go to in a browser but xn&amp;ndash;e1ance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 6: Air Conditioning and Air Traffic Control in Yokohoma</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 18:19:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-6/</guid>
      <description>Today I decided to look for more industrial control systems, specifically Mitsubishi Q-Series logic controllers.
Yokohama Air Traffic Control Tower on 133.34.157.13 Reading about them on Shodan it looks like the Q-Series logic controllers tend to run off ports 5006 or 5007. So I did a search for those open ports. Judging from the results it looks like the majority of these Mitsubishi controllers are in Japan, not surprising I suppose since Mitsubishi is a Japanese company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 5: Organic Chemistry in Poland, Ecotoxicology, and the Dangers of Static Electricity</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 13:33:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-5/</guid>
      <description>Today I decided to go looking for MySQL databases. I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved SQL, it was one of the first &amp;ldquo;programming languages&amp;rdquo; I learned and was a big part of one of my first jobs.
Institute of Industrial Organic Chemistry on 79.96.39.102 Checking with MySQL documents I found that MySQL databases typically run off of port 3306. So I went on Shodan to look for things with port 3306. One of the first results I saw was from Poland, and being Polish I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist poking around a bit in the homeland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 4: Television in Spain, Firmware Hacking in Palestine, Linux Kernels, Clone Bombs, and 14 Years of Passion</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 12:08:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-4/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw that the fifth most searched for term on Shodan of the day was &amp;ldquo;dreambox&amp;rdquo;. What a name! I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist! After a little digging I found that dreambox probably referred to a kind of linux-based television receiver, made by a German company with a truly fantastic logo. Cloned Dreambox Television Receiver on 84.39.177.219 I started out just searching on Shodan for &amp;ldquo;dreambox&amp;rdquo;, like so many others were doing today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 3: Playing Minecraft in Minnesota, Wasting Time with Catholic Teens</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 16:59:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-3/</guid>
      <description>Since I didn&amp;rsquo;t do Minecraft servers yesterday I decided to do them today. First I read a little guide on how to set up a Minecraft server to get a sense of what they looked like.
Les Chevaliers Royale Minecraft Server on 97.94.56.211 I actually don&amp;rsquo;t know much about Minecraft, I&amp;rsquo;ve never played it. I know it&amp;rsquo;s popular with a wide range of people, and that really dedicated players like to set up servers for group play, so I thought it might be interesting to look around for a server and figure out if I could find the people who were using it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 2: Joann Fabric&#39;s Sinister Plot</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 15:46:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-2/</guid>
      <description>Today I had two quick ideas for what to look for, either industrial control systems or minecraft servers. Flipping a coin, ICS won out. Reading a quick Shodan guide on them I decided to look for Siemens control systems, for no reason other than I&amp;rsquo;d heard of them before.
Joann Fabric&amp;rsquo;s Industrial Control System on 208.83.32.213 Siemens has a proprietary network protocol called S7 Communications that they use for their Programmable Logic Controllers (PLC), which they also provide a nice sales brochure for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan Stories Day 1</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 11:06:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-1/</guid>
      <description>A note up front:
Generally I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with an ethical question of this project, should I be publishing the IP addresses and personal identification of individual people I find? I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine that anyone reading this would take that info and do anything untoward with it, but it&amp;rsquo;s an odd stance on surveillance culture to dox strangers meaninglessly, even if the ability to reach out and randomly touching a stranger is the reality of networked existence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>