<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>100 Days on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</title>
    <link>http://blog.alden.website/categories/100-days/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 100 Days on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 12:08:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.alden.website/categories/100-days/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of Shodan Stories Day 4: Television in Spain, Firmware Hacking in Palestine, Linux Kernels, Clone Bombs, and 14 Years of Passion</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 12:08:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-4/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw that the fifth most searched for term on Shodan of the day was &amp;ldquo;dreambox&amp;rdquo;. What a name! I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist! After a little digging I found that dreambox probably referred to a kind of linux-based television receiver, made by a German company with a truly fantastic logo. Cloned Dreambox Television Receiver on 84.39.177.219 I started out just searching on Shodan for &amp;ldquo;dreambox&amp;rdquo;, like so many others were doing today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of Shodan Stories Day 3: Playing Minecraft in Minnesota, Wasting Time with Catholic Teens</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 16:59:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-3/</guid>
      <description>Since I didn&amp;rsquo;t do Minecraft servers yesterday I decided to do them today. First I read a little guide on how to set up a Minecraft server to get a sense of what they looked like.
Les Chevaliers Royale Minecraft Server on 97.94.56.211 I actually don&amp;rsquo;t know much about Minecraft, I&amp;rsquo;ve never played it. I know it&amp;rsquo;s popular with a wide range of people, and that really dedicated players like to set up servers for group play, so I thought it might be interesting to look around for a server and figure out if I could find the people who were using it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of Shodan Stories Day 2: Joann Fabric&#39;s Sinister Plot</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 15:46:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-2/</guid>
      <description>Today I had two quick ideas for what to look for, either industrial control systems or minecraft servers. Flipping a coin, ICS won out. Reading a quick Shodan guide on them I decided to look for Siemens control systems, for no reason other than I&amp;rsquo;d heard of them before.
Joann Fabric&amp;rsquo;s Industrial Control System on 208.83.32.213 Siemens has a proprietary network protocol called S7 Communications that they use for their Programmable Logic Controllers (PLC), which they also provide a nice sales brochure for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of Shodan Stories Day 1</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 11:06:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/100days/Day-1/</guid>
      <description>A note up front:
Generally I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with an ethical question of this project, should I be publishing the IP addresses and personal identification of individual people I find? I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine that anyone reading this would take that info and do anything untoward with it, but it&amp;rsquo;s an odd stance on surveillance culture to dox strangers meaninglessly, even if the ability to reach out and randomly touching a stranger is the reality of networked existence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>