<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello Computer on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</title>
    <link>http://blog.alden.website/categories/hello-computer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello Computer on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:46:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.alden.website/categories/hello-computer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncanny Sandra</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/hellocomp/uncanny-sandra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:46:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/hellocomp/uncanny-sandra/</guid>
      <description>Sandra I love the premise of Sandra but I can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder what kind of system could instantaneously categorize and direct all of these requests but couldn&amp;rsquo;t formulate automated responses for most of them. Does it go more into detail about what ends up happening? There is something in the show about the current economy&amp;rsquo;s preference for high-abstraction capital (algorithms, systems, connections) over labor, like the company Alia Shawkat is working for is the service economy equivalent of an old steel factory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives Made Easy</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/hellocomp/archive_made_easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:22:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/hellocomp/archive_made_easy/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a ton of books with names like &amp;ldquo;Cyber Dictionary: Your Guide To The Wired World&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Net Chick: A Smart-Girl Guide to the Wired World&amp;rdquo;, hip and breezy internet guide books written between 1996-2000. This has led to me making a few strange archive tools around the Internet Archive&amp;rsquo;s Wayback Machine
The one I made for Hello Computer this week, a voice controlled archive navigation system, can be found here but unfortunately because I don&amp;rsquo;t have HTTPS certification on my prototypes site Chrome will not allow you to access the microphone, so all you can see is the initial button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Circle</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/hellocomp/eager_icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:39:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/hellocomp/eager_icon/</guid>
      <description>In starting to make some kind of something that talks I wanted to emulate one of my favorite browser games (is it a game?) ClickClickClick. But I found that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know enough about &amp;ldquo;The DOM&amp;rdquo; to get much of my foot in the door without a bunch of research time. So instead I went an easier route, dipping into the familiar warmth of P5. I took a project that I had given a bit of a start to before, a little game about waiting around.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>