<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cabinets of wonder on Alden&#39;s Blog Home</title>
    <link>https://blog.alden.website/categories/cabinets-of-wonder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cabinets of wonder on Alden&#39;s Blog Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 23:08:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.alden.website/categories/cabinets-of-wonder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self Curation Self Curated</title>
      <link>https://blog.alden.website/post/cabofwon/self-curation-self-curated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 23:08:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.alden.website/post/cabofwon/self-curation-self-curated/</guid>
      <description>A show based on my own biography? It&amp;rsquo;s almost too much to ask, my brain feels like it&amp;rsquo;s turning over trying to keep up with the flood of associations. There&amp;rsquo;s me as a young dancer, watching William Forsythe&amp;rsquo;s Improvisation Technologies, or working with Physical Education, or reading The Collected Stories of Lydia Davis. Going to Berghain with my sister and then reading Gender Trouble all the next day without sleeping. There&amp;rsquo;s me as a young gallerist flying to New York to see the Wynn Greenwood show that such and such person had curated with the New Museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Museum of Now</title>
      <link>https://blog.alden.website/post/cabofwon/museum-of-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 21:50:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.alden.website/post/cabofwon/museum-of-now/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I imagine the world of the medium-term future looking back on the current time, say 75-100 years from now, which I do reasonably often, I imagine an intense future regret for now. It&amp;rsquo;s a hard emotion to put into words. Maybe a kind of warm nostalgia combined with disgust, the way many Americans now view the 1950s, but mixed in with the sense that this time, the early 20XXs, was a time when wrong choices were made willfully in the face of evidence pointing toward right choices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diorama of Daily Life</title>
      <link>https://blog.alden.website/post/cabofwon/diorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:16:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.alden.website/post/cabofwon/diorama/</guid>
      <description>For a daily life diorama I wanted to share one of my favorite daily activities: flossing! Construction wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard but took some ingenuity. I used a shoebox, construction paper, tissue paper, and a clear plastic egg carton for the teeth. Quite a bit of tape, and of course a piece of floss.
I really do love flossing and look forward to it every evening. When I was much younger I would never floss but I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of problems with my teeth and jaw over the years and have since become a total convert, maybe it gives me the feeling of being in control a bit more over a part of me that has been so unruly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Gore</title>
      <link>https://blog.alden.website/post/cabofwon/grant-gore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 17:37:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.alden.website/post/cabofwon/grant-gore/</guid>
      <description>The peculiarly named Grant Gore, a small triangular park at the intersection of Dean and Bedford in Crown Heights (&amp;lsquo;gore&amp;rsquo; being an obscure term for any small triangular park), is home to a truly massive bronze statue of Ulysses S Grant, Union hero of the Civil War and two term Reconstruction era president.
On a crisp morning this week I went to take a look at the statue. I was intrigued by the short bit of history I had read about it and the Gilded Age high society club that had commissioned it, but I also went because I wanted to unpack the inexplicable warmth I feel towards Grant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Museum of Natural History</title>
      <link>https://blog.alden.website/post/cabofwon/american-museum-natural-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:54:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.alden.website/post/cabofwon/american-museum-natural-history/</guid>
      <description>My first thought walking up to the Central Park West was &amp;ldquo;I hate this goddamn statue&amp;rdquo;. Teddy Roosevelt, the magnanimous colonizer, leading the Othered literal lower-thans toward civilization, away from inhumanity. The statue recontextualizes a history of violence, slavery, and cultural erasure into one of progress, benevolence, and grace. This was my first time seeing it in person and it feels like a visceral affront, hard to look at, hard to stomach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
