<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sound and Video on </title>
    <link>/categories/sound-and-video/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sound and Video on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/sound-and-video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy Lense Kickstarter Campaign</title>
      <link>/2017/10/20/empathy-lense-kickstarter-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/20/empathy-lense-kickstarter-campaign/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;#8217;d like to thank Jason, Rick, and most importantly of all, Archibald! Thanks to bensound.com for the use of his music.
&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infomercial Brainstorming and Storyboard</title>
      <link>/2017/10/02/infomercial-brainstorming-and-storyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/02/infomercial-brainstorming-and-storyboard/</guid>
      <description>Initial Ideas
As you can see from the above picture Amitabh, Martin, and I had a few different ideas, but we settled on a device that takes the way in which online human communications are mediated via AI algorithms and replicates it in the real world. We debated for a while what form we wanted this to take &amp;#8211; either a consumer level device for facial recognition for emotion or an AI that determines political leanings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Walk</title>
      <link>/2017/09/22/sound-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/22/sound-walk/</guid>
      <description>Episode 19 of the 4th season of Creature Feature, made by Shreiya and Alden. Please start on the 12th floor of the Tisch building, just outside of elevator bank A. And don&amp;#8217;t forget to walk slow and really take in your surroundings!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Janet Cardiff Sound Walk and Reading Response</title>
      <link>/2017/09/14/janet-cardiff-sound-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/14/janet-cardiff-sound-walk/</guid>
      <description>For several hours after I finished Her Long Black Hair, Janet Cardiff&amp;#8217;s Central Park sound walk combining field recording, found object and narrative techniques of film noir, I felt a heightened awareness of the world around me, a sense that both the aural and visual information I was consuming had hidden narratives, meanings unknown to me, entire words and lives just beyond the field of my comprehension. This sense of hidden but pulsating alive connectivity is the central goal of Cardiff&amp;#8217;s work: to create connections within time between the walker/listener and the spaces and strangers around them, and to create connections across time, between the walker/listener, the woman with black hair, Orpheus descending into Hades to rescue Eurydice, and Cardiff herself, connecting and condensing these moments of time and myth into a gem of experiential authenticity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>