<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Performative Avatars on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</title>
    <link>http://blog.alden.website/categories/performative-avatars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Performative Avatars on Alden&#39;s ITP Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 15:07:58 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.alden.website/categories/performative-avatars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rig Me</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/avatars/rig-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 15:07:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/avatars/rig-me/</guid>
      <description>All my rigged, texture, .obj files located here.
Had a ton of fun with my body once I rigged it. I realized in this process that I need to rescan myself if I want a more real world vision of my body because I wore my glasses during my scan and they aren&amp;rsquo;t showing up super good on my body digitally. Whoops! Here are two of my favorite animations Scattershot (I&amp;rsquo;m very sleepy today), responses to the readings:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digi Me</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/post/avatars/digi-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 22:50:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/post/avatars/digi-me/</guid>
      <description>This week the phrase &amp;ldquo;digital avatars&amp;rdquo; has kept making me think of Digimon. I don&amp;rsquo;t think Digimon ever really established what exactly happened to these kids when they entered the DigiWorld. Was their meatbody converted to bits and code? They pass back and forth between the barrier several times, which to me seems like a painful transition.
I worked with Nico and Kim doing 3D body scans with itSeez3D. We did a lot of scans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Avatars</title>
      <link>http://blog.alden.website/2018/09/11/two-avatars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.alden.website/2018/09/11/two-avatars/</guid>
      <description>Part of my interest in digital avatars stems from their existence for me as a place of identity building and actualization. Being able to create and visualize new images of myself has been empowering and intoxicating force (additionally for several years, until I was banned, I [consciously and intentionally, rather than through workaday self-curation] treated my Facebook as a sandbox identity separate from my physical meat body, which I think made me both alluring and confusing to acquaintances).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>