<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Language on Alden&#39;s ITP Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/visual-language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual Language on Alden&#39;s ITP Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 03:53:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/visual-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Card</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2017/10/18/business-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 03:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2017/10/18/business-card/</guid>
      <description>Side A of the business card:
I really liked the hands and eyes that I had going in my show poster, so I decided that I wanted the same kind of thing for my business card. I wasn&amp;#8217;t really sure what to put for my &amp;#8220;title&amp;#8221; so that is just a placeholder for now. The font I used was &amp;#8220;Gil Sans&amp;#8221; and I took my Twitter and Github icons from their media packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ITP Winter Show Card</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2017/10/11/itp-winter-show-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 14:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2017/10/11/itp-winter-show-card/</guid>
      <description>Initially I wanted to make something inspired by Tadanori Yokoo. I spent a lot of time futzing around with different elements but I ultimately decided what I liked was the simplest, a little line drawing reaching out to the show information, giving a sense of playfulness. I really like this color contrast but I think it might be a little distracting. I put a less contrast version on the bottom of the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Color Palette</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2017/10/04/personal-color-palette/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 03:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2017/10/04/personal-color-palette/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
I took my color palette from my twitter avi (drawn by Norah Horwitz). From there I created several pattern using P5.js inspired by 90s design, current brutalist web design, and art deco. You can see the code here.
&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boarding Pass and Expressive Words</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2017/09/27/boarding-pass-and-expressive-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 02:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2017/09/27/boarding-pass-and-expressive-words/</guid>
      <description>On first glance of a boarding pass I notice not just a jumble of information poorly organized, but too much information, a heaping mass of which obscures the information that the traveller is really am interested in when they have a pass in hand.
The date is unnecessary, a traveler would only be receiving this pass on the day of the flight. Origin and destinations are also unnecessary; we must assume that they have knowledge of their destination and current locations already in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign Research</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2017/09/19/sign-intervention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 23:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2017/09/19/sign-intervention/</guid>
      <description>I started out my sign research scouting by going to the Rob Rauschenberg show at MoMA. Rauschenberg makes copious use of street signage, here are a couple of examples:
Decontextualizing signs makes them jarring, bringing them much more to the forefront of our consciousness than they occupy in their usual streetside homes.
(*\* if you are reading this it means that my webhost is terrible and will not let me upload a picture of Hans Deli&amp;#8217;s sign I took &amp;#8211; what I have to say about it is that it is simple, effective, and purposeful **)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akira Poster Design Analysis</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2017/09/13/48/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:42:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2017/09/13/48/</guid>
      <description>Visually striking and iconic* &amp;#8211; the original poster for the film Akira brings forth a sense of encroaching gloom, of decay, of violence, all with a startling minimalism. The film depicts the country of Japan at a time of crisis, evoked here in the poster by centering the colors of the Japanese flag and surrounding them with creeping, looming shadows of blue-grey.
The eye is immediately drawn by the image organization and the blue splash on his jacket toward the figure in the center, bringing him front and center to the poster and indicating that he is, if not the lead character, at least central to the film.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>